A Seminal Journey of Self-Discovery.
Christopher and His Kind is a drama, romance, tv
movie film directed by Geoffrey Sax.
In 1931, budding author Christopher Isherwood goes to
Berlin at the invitation of his friend W.
Auden for the gay sex that abounds in the city.
He falls for street sweeper Heinz, paying medical bills for the boy's sickly
mother, to the disapproval of her other son, Nazi Gerhardt.
Christopher Isherwood, played by Matt Smith.
Jean Ross, played by Imogen Poots.
Kathleen Isherwood, played by Lindsay Duncan.
Richard Isherwood, played by Perry Milward.
Gerald Hamilton, played by Toby Jones.
W. H. Auden, played by Pip Carter.
Christopher and His Kind is a 2011 BBC television film.
It tells the story of Christopher Isherwood's
exploits in Berlin in the early 1930s.
The film, adapted by Kevin Elyot from Isherwood's autobiography Christopher and His
Kind, was produced by Mammoth Screen and directed by Geoffrey Sax.
Isherwood is played by Matt Smith, whilst the cast also includes Douglas Booth,
Imogen Poots, Pip Carter, Toby Jones, and Alexander Dreymon.
The film explores themes of germany, world war ii, based on true
story, misfit, based on memoir or autobiography.
The tone is emotional.